Beschrijving van de collection Cornelis Hendrik van Schooneveld
Universiteitsbibliotheek Leiden
- Scholarly notes and manuscripts (inv. nos. 26-30)., C.
  - Miscellaneous., 30.; Master copies of articles and various notes.; 6 boxes.
    - Master copies of articles.
      32. The place of gender in the semantic structure of the Russian language.
      33. Untitled.
      34. Article on morphology for Sofia '63.
      35. A theory of verbal lexical meaning.
      36. Drawings for Semantic transmutations.
      37. MLA Christmas 1979.
      38. Primitive terms.
      39. Greek verbs.
      40. Post Scriptum.
      41. Word categories.
      42. The central semantic structure of Russian, Los Angeles 1978.
      43. Werner-Gren fellowship 1952.
      44. 5 'originals'.
      45. A semantic approach to the analysis of word formation in contemporary standard Russian.
      46. Autopoiesis - Athens preprint 1982.
      47. Three examples of narrated speech in Pushkin's 'Poltava'.
      48. Semantic proteus: the transitivity feature in Russian.
      49. Festschrift for Native speaker article.
      50. Haas article.
      51. The extension feature in Russian.
      52. In my book ...
      53. Unsent letters.
    - Notes.
      54. B.B. Becker Festschrift.
      55. Various notes.
      56. Bibliographic notes.
- Scholarly documentation (inv. nos. 31-36)., D.
  - Conference papers., 31.; Hand-outs relating to conferences Van Schooneveld attended.; 6 boxes.
    1. Comparative study of Slavonic Languages, Olomouc and Prague, January 28-February 2, 1957.
    2. Warsaw, 1958.
    3. Warsaw, August 1960.
    4. Conference on Indo-European Linguistics: 'Ancient Indo-European dialects and their grouping' UCLA, April 25-27, 1963.
    5. Far Western Slavic Conference, Stanford, April 27, 1963.
    6. Romania.
    7. The First International Roman Jakobson Conference, New York, October 10-13, 1985.
  - Stanford University., 32.; Internal items from Stanford University from the period (1960-1966) when Van Schooneveld was professor at this university.; 3 boxes.
    1. Attribution of predication.
    2. General recommendations.
    3. Stanford policy.
    4. Stanford Studies in International conflict and Integration.
    5. Stanford Research Club.
    6. Housing.
    7. Library of Congress.
    8. Stanford Faculty Club.
    9. Faculty Room.
    10. Graduate awards.
    11. Academic council.
    12. Committee on International Studies.
    13. Committee on Promotions and Appointments.
    14. Committee on Public Exercises.
    15. Executive Committee School of Humanities and Sciences.
    16. Faculty Seminar on Eastern Europe.
    17. Library Development Fund Comm.
    18. MEL Library Committee.
    19. Russian appointment.
    20. Subcommittee on libraries.
    21. Stanford Studies of the Communist System.
    22. Committee on linguistics.
    23. Committee on linguistics: appointments.
    24. Committee on linguistics: minutes.
    25. Asian Languages Program.
    26. Department of Communication.
    27. School of Education.
    28. Foreign Student Adviser.
    29. Graduate Program in Humanities.
    30. Humanities and Sciences Honors Program.
    31. Linguistics.
    32. Placement.
    33. Registrar.
    34. Stanford Speech Pathology and Audiology.
    35. Stanford Police Department.
    36-45. vacant.
    46. Visser, Wanda.
    47. Graduate Students - General.
    48. Examination: Synchronic phonology (SL 201).
    49. Examination: Synchronic phonology (SL 203).
    50. Examination: East Slavic Diachrony (SL 221).
    51. Examination (SL 222).
    52. Papers by students.
    53. Students 1960-61, 1961-62.
    54. Linguistics 180 Exam.
    55. Examination: SL 250, Fall and Winter 1965-1966.
    56. Winter quarter exams 1964-1965.
    57. Inter-University Committee on travel grants.
    58. Lisle Fellowships.
    59. NDEA 1960.
    60. NDEA 1961.
    61. NDEA Selection Committee 1962.
    62. NDFL Committee 1963.
    63. NDFL Committee 1964-65.
    64. Graduate Apllication Information.
    65. MEL Advanced degrees (non-Slavic).
    66. Teaching credentials.
    67. Recommendations for students and teachers.
    68. Tutoring.
  - Indiana University., 33.; Internal items from Indiana University from the period (1966-1986) when Van Schooneveld was professor at this university.; 3 boxes.
    1. Prehláska paper.
    2. Enrollment cards.
    3. Evaluations by students.
    4. Library.
    5. Library acquisition suggestions.
    6. Referendum ballot.
    7. International Affairs Center.
    8. Linguistics Department.
    9. Indiana University Linguistics Club.
    10. Recommendations for foreign language requirements at Indiana University.
    11. 1974, 1976 Sabbatical application.
    12. Slavic Departmental Chairmanship 1972-1973.
    13. Indiana University & CHvS.
    14. Indiana University Linguistics Newsletter.
    15. Slavic Department - General business.
    16. Women's affairs.
    17. MAIRSK.
    18. Dean John Lombardi.
    19. One messy etc. chairmanship file.
    20. Dissertations in progress.
    21. Faculty research grant.
    22. Research projects.
    23. Leave information.
    24. Indiana seminars.
    25. Search committee, Slavic Department chairman.
    26. Committee for search for V.P, & dean for academic affairs (1972).
    27. Preparation of promotion dossiers.
    28. vacant.
    29. A.A.U.P.
    30. Computer approaches - literature.
    31. Distinguished & name professorships.
    32. Facetious.
    33. Faculty-course evaluation forms.
    34. Faculty exchange opportunities.
    35. Faculty reports.
    36. HASSLE (committee).
    37. Jobs open.
    38. Insurance, health, blue cross, blue shield.
    39. Jankowsky & Georgetown university summer language programs.
    40. Language & tool review committee.
    41. Leave 1983-1984: Dean of Faculties memo.
    42. ACLS recommendation forms.
    43. Postage 1976.
    44. Postage - Summer 1977.
    45. Postage - Summer 1978.
    46. Postage 1979, 1980.
    47. Russian & East European Institute.
    48. Slavic Department: Course: cultural history of the Russian language.
    49. Slavic Department: Course in Georgian.
    50. Slavic Department: Graduate student organization.
    51. Slavic Department: Office procedures & policies.
    52. Slavic Department: Seminar in Slavic linguistics I & II.
    53. Slavic Department reorganization.
    54. Slavic Summer Workshop.
    55. Slavic Department: Title VI proposal for academic year 1971-1972, 1972-1973.
    56. Slavic Department: courses in Slavic linguistics to be offered Fall 1972.
    57. Slavic Department: Graduate advisers and advisees - Fall 1972.
    58. Slavic Department: M.A. program.
    59. Slavic Department: M.A. exams - examples.
    60. Slavic Department: Dissertations topics.
    61. Slavic Department: Ph.D. examination information.
    62. Slavic Department: Teaching schedules 1970-1971, 1971-1972.
    63. Slavic Department: Course: advanced structure of Russian, I: phonology and morphology, II: lexicology.
    64. Slavic Department: Course: Comparative Slavic, South Slavic.
    65-74. vacant.
    75. Telephone Service.
    76. Tenure policy.
    77. University Club.
    78. Wage freeze & Indiana University salaries.
    79. Work orders.
  - Slavistics and general linguistics., 34.; Items from scholarly committees, learned societies, associations, and journals, in Europe as well as in the United States, in the area of Slavistics and general linguistics.; 5 boxes.
    1. American Association of Teachers of Slavic and East European Languages.
    2. American Association of University Professors (AAUP).
    3. AAUP Newsletter.
    3bis. Academia Scientiarum Fennica.
    4. Algemene Vereniging voor Taalwetenschap.
    5. Alliance Française.
    6. American Anthropological Association.
    7. American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies (AAASS).
    8. American Bibliography of Slavic and East European Studies.
    9. American Committee for the Liberation.
    10. American Committee of Slavists.
    11. American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS).
    12. American Institute for Foreign Study.
    13. American Philological Association.
    14. Arms of Friendship.
    15. Association internationale d'études du sud-est europeén (AIESEE).
    16. Association internationale des langues et littératures slaves.
    17. Association internationale de phonologie.
    18. Association of Russian-American scholars.
    19. Collegium Carolinum München.
    20. Committee for International Friendly Visits.
    21. Committee for the Promotion of Advanced Slavic Cultural Studies.
    22. Committee on Institutional Cooperation.
    23. ERIC Clearinghouse for linguistics.
    24. European Association for American Studies.
    25. Experiment in International Living.
    26. Far West Slavic Conference Directory.
    27. FLANC.
    28. Foreign Area Fellowship Program.
    29. Foreign Language Association of Northern California.
    30. Gesellschaft für Ost- und Südostkunde.
    31. Information Center for American Travellers to the Soviet Union.
    32. Institut für Phonetik und Kommunikationswissenschaft.
    33. Institute of Social Studies.
    34. Instituut voor Dialectologie, Volkskunde en Naamkunde.
    35. Instituut voor Internationale Culturele Betrekkingen.
    36. International Association of Slavonic Languages & Literatures.
    37. International Committee of Slavists: Commissions.
    38. International Congress of Phonetic Sciences.
    39. International Linguistic Association.
    40. International Society of Phonetic Sciences.
    41. International Journal of American Linguistics.
    42. International Seminar for Students in Russian language and Literature.
    43. Kussoth Foundation.
    44. Librarianship Institute.
    45. Linguistic Agency University at Trier.
    46. International Linguistic Association (formerly The Linguistic Circle of New York).
    47. Linguistics Group.
    48. Linguistic Society of America.
    49. Midwest Modern Languages Association.
    50. Modern Language Association.
    51. MLA Newsletter.
    52. National Association of Independent Schools, Russian Committee.
    53. National Endowment for the Humanities Program Announcement.
    54. National Student Association.
    55. Nederlandse Vereniging voor Phonetische Wetenschappen.
    56. Nederlandse Vereniging voor Toegepaste Taalkunde.
    57. Nederlandse Vereniging voor Toegepaste Taalwetenschap.
    58. Nobel Committee of the Swedish Academy.
    59. Nomen.
    60. Orbis Litterarum.
    61. Outside Russia.
    62. Philological Association of the Pacific Coast.
    63. Poetics and Theory of Literature.
    64. Semiotic Society of America.
    65. Slavic Review.
    66. Slavische Studievereniging.
    67. Slavjanski Komitet v Bǎlgarija.
    68. Societas Linguistica Europaea.
    69. Societé de linguistique de Paris.
    70. Society for Applied Dutch Linguistics.
    71. Society for Slovene Studies.
    72. Societé pour l'information grammaticale.
    73. Sociëteit Minerva.
    74. Tenth International Congress of Linguistics (1967).
    75. Travel & Study, Inc.
    76. USIA.
    77. Vydatelstvo Slovenskej Akademie Vied.
    78. Wasson Committee.
    79. Western Slavic Association.
    80. Who's Who in America.
    81. Who's Who in the World.
    82. Yugoslav & Soviet Exchange.
  - Bookstores and publishing houses., 35.; Items from and about bookstores and publishing houses, in alphabetical order by company.; 3 boxes.
    1. Akademische Druck- u. Verlagsanstalt.
    2. Amiram Verlag.
    3. Ars Polona.
    4. Artia.
    5. J.J. Augustin Publishers.
    6. Blackwell's.
    7. Boeken Import Bureau.
    8. Bouma's Boekhuis.
    9. Brill.
    10. Bretschneider.
    11. Burgersdijk & Niermans.
    12. University of California Press.
    13. Cambridge University Press.
    14. Cankarjeva Založba.
    15. Collet's.
    16. Cracovia Book Co. Ltd.
    17. Deutscher Buch-Export und -Import GmbH.
    18. Editorial Gredos.
    19. Fam Book Service.
    20. Farrar, Straus & Co.
    21. R.P.R. Filiala Cluj (Prof. Macrea).
    22. Four Continents Book Corp.
    23. Funk & Wagnall.
    24. J.H. Gottmer.
    25. J. Ginsberg.
    26. Harper & Row.
    27. Otto Harrassowitz.
    28. Harvard Linguistics Department.
    29. Harvard University Library.
    30. Harvard University Press.
    31. W. Heffer & Sons.
    32. Hemphill's Book Stores.
    33. Henry Holt.
    34. Humanities Press.
    35. Johnson Reprint Corporation.
    36. S. Karger A.G.
    37. N.V. Boekhandel v.h. C. Kooyker.
    38. Kubon & Sagner.
    39. Kultura.
    39bis. Firma Langerveld.
    40. Book orders.
    41. Booksellers - varia.
    42. I.C.E. Libri.
    43. Le Livre Étranger.
    44. Lingua.
    45. Linguistic Society of America.
    46. Maison Descartes.
    47. Magnes Press.
    48. Michigan Slavic Materials.
    49. Microfilms: Nederlandse Document Reproductie.
    50. Microfilms - information.
    51. MIT Press.
    52. University of Minnesota Press.
    53. Mouton-booksellers.
    54. Ejnar Munksgaard.
    55. Neimanis.
    56. University of North Carolina Press.
    57. North Holland Publishing Co.
    58. W.W. Norton & Comp.
    59. G.A. van Oorschot.
    60. Orbis.
    61. Out-of-Print Book Center.
    62. Oxford University Press.
    63. Pan Books.
    64. Pánstwowe Wydawnictwo Popularno Naukowe.
    65. Pegasus.
    66. Horst Pelz.
    67. I. Perlstein.
    68. F.W. Peters.
    69. Albert J. Phiebig.
    70. Poland - book orders.
    71. Prentice-Hall.
    72. Prosveta.
    73. Raznoiznos.
    73bis. Rohrscheid, Ludwig.
    74. Russ-Book.
    75. Russica.
    76. Sanskrit.
    77. Scandinavian History.
    78. Schallenberg.
    79. A.W. Sijthoff.
    80. Simon and Schuster.
    81. M. Slatkine & Fils.
    82. J. de Slegte.
    83. Slovak Institute.
    84. Stanford University Press.
    85. Periodical subscriptions.
    86. Summer Institute of Linguistics.
    87. Swets & Zeitlinger N.V.
    88. Szwede Gallery & Bookstore.
    89. Dr. K. Tschenkeli.
    90. Uitgeverij Het Spectrum N.V.
    91. University Microfilms.
    92. E. Violet.
    93. Carl Winter.
    94. Word.
    95. William Young & Co.
    96. Zentral-Antiquariat der Deutschen Demokratischen Republik.
    97. Znanie Book Store.
    98. Zora.
  - Miscellaneous., 36.; Papers relating to Nicolaas van Wijk.; 1 folder.
    1. Postcard of B. Kruitwagen to Van Wijk dated August, 12, 1940.
    2. Picture of Van Wijk.
    3. Typescript of Van Wijk's article 'Le rôle de l'accent dans les langues slaves'.
    4. Notes by Van Wijk.
    5. Off-print of an article by Petr Bogatyrev with a handwritten dedication to Van Wijk dated January 22, 1936.
- Personal papers (inv. nos. 37-39)., E.
  - Documents., 37.; Various personal documents.; 1 box.
    1. Passport photographs.
    2. Birth certificate from the Register Office, Den Haag, dated February 28, 1951.
    3. Certificate of Leiden Gymnasium, 1938.
    4. Documents on military service, 1939-1949.
    5. Certificate of bachelor's degree (Slavic languages, Leiden University), 1941.
    6. Documents relating to work in the Leiden University Library, 1941-1942.
    7. Card of Raad van Arbeid, Leiden, 1944.
    8. Appointment as teacher of Russian and Old Church Slavonic at Leiden University, 1945.
    9. Certificate of masters degree (Slavic languages, Leiden University), 1946.
    10. Four menus, Sociëteit Minerva, 1946-1955.
    11. Seaman's card, 1947.
    12. U.S. Merchant Mariner's Document, 1947.
    13. Certificate of his removal from the register of the Gereformeerde Kerk, Leiden, 1951.
    14. Documents relating to marriage to Elizabeth Manby Starck, Cambridge, Mass., 1952.
    15. Leiden Municipality, certificate from the register office, 1953.
    16. Documents relating to Elizabeth Manby Starck.
    17. Statement by Dutch consul-general in San Francisco, 1959.
    18. Documents relating to trips to Czechoslovakia and the Soviet Union.
    19. Medical documents.
    20. Driving licences and other documents relating to cars.
    21. Social Security Account Card.
    22. Photocopies of passports.
  - Miscellaneous., 38.; Diaries, mail logs and various documents.; 7 boxes.
    - Diaries.
      1. Diary 1963-1964.
      2. Diary 1: 1972-1985.
      3. Diary 2: 1985-1988.
      4. Diary 3: 1986 (Soviet Union).
      5. Diary 1989.
      6. Diary 1993.
    - Directories.
      7. Directory I.
      8. Directory IIA.
      9. Directory III.
      10. Directory IV.
    - Mail logs.
      11. Mail log 1956-.
      12. Mail log 1959-.
      13. Mail log 1961-1964.
      14. Mail log 1964-1967.
      15. Mail log 1964-1970.
      16. Mail log 1968-1970.
      17. Mail log 1967-1968.
      18. Mail log 1970-1971.
      19. Mail log 1971-1974.
      20. Mail log 1974-1976.
      21. Mail log 1976-1980.
      22. Mail log 1980-1985.
      23. Mail log 1985-1991.
      24. Mail log 1986.
      25. Mail log 1991-1995.
      26. Mail log 1995-2003.
      27. Vozérier mail log 1981- (loose leaves).
    - Mail logs concerning off-prints, manuscripts and publishers.
      28. Mailing list of off-prints.
      29. Manuscripts received 1.
      30. Manuscripts received 2 + 1971 mail logs + Summer 1972 mail log.
      31. Manuscripts mailed, 1971-1980.
      32. Bloomington Translation Group 1.
      33. Bloomington Translation Group 2.
      34. Bloomington Translation Group 3.
      35. Physsardt 1982-1989.
      36. Mouton Expense account.
    - Columbia University.
      37. Documents relating to study and promotion at Columbia University.
    - Career.
      38. Leiden appointment (1952-1959).
      39. Harvard University (1952-1955).
      40. Stanford Universiy (1960-1966).
      41. Applications relating to various universities.
      42. Dissertation thank-you's (1959).
    - Curriculum vitae, bibliography and articles on C.H. van Schooneveld.
      43. Curriculum vitae.
      44. Bibliography of works by C.H. van Schooneveld.
      45. Reviews and interviews.
    - Various subjects.
      46. Summer house in Vozérier-Amancy: documents and photographs.
      47. Recordings: 3 cassettes with interviews by Françoise Gadet.
      48. Books borrowed forms.
      49. Notarial act, 1963.
  - Commentary, correspondence and documents concerning the collection., 39.; Manuscripts and letters relating to the C.H. van Schooneveld collection and to the library of C.H. van Schooneveld.; 1 box.
    - Commentary.
      1. Van Schooneveld's handwritten commentaries on drafts of the printed catalogue of the collection.
    - Correspondence with Leiden University Library, 1998-2002.
      2. Correspondence with André Bouwman, curator of Western manuscripts.
      3. Correspondence with Jan Paul Hinrichs, Slavic librarian.
    - Varia.
      4. Correspondence regarding attempts to sell the library of C.H. van Schooneveld.